I would like you to give it up for Amit.
Kushwaha from NVIDIA.
Whilst Amit is getting set up I will.
Realize I haven't
got all my notes on my machine.
So you're going to be talking about benchmarking the agent era:
the agent era and you're ready to go, so I will leave you to it.
Thank you. Thank you very much, Amit.
My name is Amit.
I'm a principal solutions architect at NVIDIA,
and we live in the
Deep Learning Solutions Department.
And one of the most important things that we care about
will have benchmarks that will present real-world workloads.
However, these benchmarks have been changing over the last six
last one and a half years.
We started with simple chat bot applications
where now we are prepared into the agent.
There is no more single input output.
It's much more complex. Workflows are running.
Agents are calling multiple tools dealing with multiple context lengths.
However, the benchmarking has not kept up with it.
So in the next 30 minutes I'm going to talk about three three things one
what does the agent benchmark look workload looks like?
Second, what are the optimizations that already exist to run these
workloads efficiently?
And third, what will the current benchmarks actually miss?
And I'm going to conclude with giving an example
of a given example of a benchmark that is trying to close that gap
and then also share some learnings on what is in the future,
what is still missing, and what we still need to kind of cover up.
Before we start, let's
look at what exactly has changed.
So on the left, what you see is the kind of old chatbot that when I say
old chatbot data, what you mean is most of the conversations are single turn.
You asked a question, you get a response back.
Context were very small from one K to 4K tokens.
The output tokens were also small.
Depending on what kind of questions you are asking,
you typically get a shorter response.
So the context means that the LLMs were producing as output was much smaller
wherever there was no concept of tools, these agents
or these applications were not using tools.
Now, in the agentic workloads, what we are seeing there are dozens of tool calls.
And I'll give you concrete examples of what I mean.
The LLMs are getting called multiple times.
The context lengths have exploded from tens of thousands
to hundreds of thousands. Context lengths.
The output tokens are also increased from hundreds
to thousands of tokens that these LLMs are producing.
And we are using tools.
Having most of these workloads are using different kinds of tools
to achieve the tasks that we have asked them to do.
So the benchmark that scored yesterday on this slide doesn't
say anything about the real workloads that are currently exist.
And before
we talk about benchmarking agent workflows, let look.
Let's look at a simple example of what an agent workload looks like
here.
The the user is actually asking the LLM
to fix a flaky test in their code base.
So this is a user input.
After that you see a series of calls.
This is where the LLM takes the user input, comes back with a response.
And the response in this case is oh, go and check this certain
file and grab certain things in this file
based on that response.
Now a tool is run,
and this tool could be anything that is sitting on your Linux terminal.
It could be bash scripts, it could be graphs, it could be web search.
And then it keeps on doing that.
It feeds that input back to the LLMs at the new information,
provides a new response, and tell it to go and look into the next file.
Then the tool goes and gets into the next part.
So this this whole trajectory where you have a single user input in the
beginning can go on for 20 to 40 times, depending on how complex the workflow is.
And a few things to note here.
The portion in green is what is being run by or what is running on a GPU.
The portion on in purple is typically run on on CPUs, so it's
kind of a mix of a workload where GPU and CPU kind of interplay to solve it.
Whole problem.
And just to reiterate what I said, one user message can lead to 20 to 40 tool calls.
Most of the tokens that are
generated are actually at this step when you are calling the two.
This is where most of the tokens are being generated.
The two lists, calling multiple files, reading multiple files,
and then feeding that information attack into the other well.
So that's where kind of the most tokens are input.
And the output tokens are very small.
And the reason
being the output of the LLMs are typically just calling to discuss
giving small instructions on what to do, which tool to call, and how to call it.
So typically what you see is the output tokens are much smaller
than what we would have seen in the older era.
And again, this is an example for a coding agent.
So the talk will be mostly focused on the coding agent side of things.
This workload might look different
if you are talking about different kinds of agent.
But here the focus is primarily on the coding agents.
So looking at that workload, there are few optimizations
that are already kind of present in the production systems.
And these are very critical to make that workload work.
Again, going back to kind of the current
setup that I shared in the previous slide, in the first turn,
this is your user input and you get an output in the second turn.
This whole thing could be cached.
And this is the optimization
that I'm talking about for most of the agent workloads.
Caching becomes very, very important because what you are doing is piling up.
By the time you are at the 40th turn,
a lot of context has been created, but you don't need to do all the work.
If you are caching your output inputs properly, then you only need to do
work on the new tokens that are being generated in this whole workflow.
So at the end of kind of this, this 40th turn, for example,
most of this is cached and you don't have to do any work on it.
The new part is only where you run your GPUs and actually to make the work,
if the caching was not enabled, you can imagine
a lot more work needs to be done, and there's consequences
on one performance on time to first token and different kinds of metrics.
So caching becomes kind of a must have in most of these agentic workloads.
And as you see, the
vast majority of output input tokens by the end could be cached
because it's just building up on the previous display.
The caching itself is not the full story,
especially when you are serving these models on multiple replicas.
Your turns have to kind of get on the right replica.
For example, if you turn one in, the previous slide landed on replica one,
and this is just an example of you could have a model serving multiple times.
So these are three replicas
of the same model that you are using neural network things.
So turn one ended up on replica K.
If you do a round robin kind of a setup
the turn you might end up on some other replica.
But this replica does not have the cache that we talked about.
So the other thing that becomes very important in a
kind of setup is to make sure that your turns
land on the same replica where your cache is stored.
So this is what is kind of shown here in KV cache-aware routing,
where turn one lands on replica one, we make sure that the turn
two also lands on replica one, so that we can leverage the cache
that is stored already on that side.
And so there are multiple ways of doing the session idea.
We just keep track of the session and make sure whatever request
was served on one replica actually goes to the same replica.
Or you can do more clean, cache-aware kind of setup.
Okay,
so it's just K and V matrices you can think about.
And the LLM world this is how you store the history.
And it's kind of a maybe I should have explained.
It's a very generic term that is used in a language.
You can think of it as storing the history of what we have already
been.
So both
these optimizations that I talked about are on the pre-filled side.
So this is where the input is getting to your elements.
Now the other the third kind of optimization that
that goes into an agentic workload is on the decoder side.
So there are two workloads for a large language model.
One is when you provide your input and the LLLM is just the input,
and the second is when the LLM starts producing the output.
So the first set of prefix caching in cash primarily deals on the pre-fill phase.
On the pre-fill side of the input side, this optimization is on the output side.
When the LLLM starts producing the output, how can you make that output
go as fast as possible?
And this is where this optimization on
speculative decoding is becoming very, very common.
The high level idea is
this is the input to your big model.
And what happens is a small model called the draft
model helps this big model to go fast.
And the way it does it, you provide the input.
The draft model, which is much smaller, can run way faster than the larger model.
So it produces these four tokens.
It says Brown fox soft over
the job of target model.
The big model is just to verify these tokens.
And it can do that in a single request.
And that's where the efficiency comes in.
So you start with an input.
The small model goes and predicts four tokens in advance.
The big model comes in and just checks all these four tokens in one row.
And this is where you get the efficiency.
So in the end what ends up happening is you produce three tokens in just one task.
Whereas if you didn't have this step of speculative decoding,
the large model would have had to produce these tokens one by one.
So roughly you can think you get three times
the speed up just by using the speculative decoder.
And there are multiple flavors of speculative decoding.
One is where actually go and train these draft models.
You have.
You use the data from the big model and then train the small draft models.
What is happening?
More and more, these draft models are coming back with the model itself.
So you might have heard about the terminology multi token prediction MDPs,
which is basically these draft tokens coming back with the new models.
So you can essentially just turn it on.
And your model should be able to use this optimization one right away without
having to do much.
So as I said three tokens in one pass.
And I'll come to the caveat.
And I have a slide that will show what what happens when you do this.
But essentially I talked about three optimizations
prefix caching cache and then speculative decoding.
The reason I talked about them, because these are kind of the foundational
optimizations that you would do for Agent Perkins.
Whereas if you looked at the current existing benchmarks,
it doesn't capture all the complexity that I just talked about.
Most of the current benchmarks used fixed states.
That means if you have done any sort of benchmarking,
if you are trying to answer the question, oh, I have a particular workload,
how many did you use?
I need what typically is done.
You choose your cell and our cell and strictly a fixed value.
So you keep the shape fixed.
You don't have any tuple calls.
This this is on the left is basically the current status or the benchmark.
It looks like fixed input output.
No tool talks.
And most of the optimizations that I just talked about are turned off
and a single time.
So no concept of multi terminal.
You're talking about project Tree which is completely different
from what we see in agentic workloads at the particle level.
Now what we miss there is no fixed.
As I saw the project tree keeps growing as you are interacting with your system.
It's collecting information from the tool and the information to the LLMs
continuously grown so the fixed chip misses the fiction.
There is no concept of multithreading in this original benchmarking board.
Most of the optimizations that I talked about prefix caching Korea,
where and speculatively coding are mostly turned off and no tools.
And that's where the that's where the main issue is.
The performance that we are measuring right now
doesn't represent the real workload.
It's not just this slide.
When you talk about agent workflows, even talking about performance
become a little tricky. You can't talk about means and medians.
Now you have to talk about in terms of distributions.
And what I'm showing here is kind of two distributions.
And you can think of the first one is time to first token.
So this is how fast you get the token back from the elm.
The right one is token speed.
So how fast you took your element is producing the tokens.
And the way you produce these histograms.
You run your workload against the hardware.
You capture all the requests that are going to your large language models.
You, you, you
collect all the time to first tokens that you get from these requests.
And you create the system Ram.
So left is good.
That means you are getting your response back very fast.
In this
right is bad.
That means your token is taking longer and longer for you,
taking longer and longer for you to get better at once.
Whereas on the on the other distribution
left is bad because that's slow generation of tokens.
Right is good.
You're generating more tokens and the way
and your user experience kind of dies on those tails.
So even if a lot of your requests sit in this,
if the users start experiencing this tail, their experience is going to be hurt.
So you want to make sure you clip these P90 five to a reasonable register
that kind of matches with your customers experience.
So all this slide is trying to say in the agent workload
you can't just stop about mean median.
You have to look at distributions.
You have to talk about metrics in terms of distributions in terms of P90
five, P25 and P90 five.
If you don't remember, your stats will be 9595 of the request.
95% of the request have time to first open better than this value.
P25 means
75% of the request have faster speed than that.
2520. The.
So this is this is kind of a
deeper dive on the distribution.
So ignore if you don't kind of follow this slide.
But just wanted to mention this
again I'm plotting the same distribution that was in the previous
slide for speed how fast you took concept using the speed.
But now I have two distributions
on the green one I have speculated decoding on.
So this is the optimization that I talked about where you can generate
three tokens in one year versus just waiting at a time.
And what you see is the distribution is towards the right.
So the speeds in general are much higher for this.
Distribution with with MPP or speculative decoding
on whereas distribution for for blue, which does not have speculatively coded
on, is actually much slower than than the other one.
But if you're not looking at the right metric, for example,
if I look at the P5 value, which is 95% of
my requests are producing outputs faster than this value for this distribution,
and 95% of my requests are producing faster tokens than this value.
For this distribution,
your situation will be reversed.
The green looks worse here, whereas the blue looks better
and which is not the complete picture.
You are actually penalizing a very good optimization where most of your requests
are actually sitting on the right side, just because you chose the wrong.
In this sense, I'm saying wrong, but for some people, maybe
five is the criteria that they don't want to satisfy.
For our case, what turned out was instead of P5, we should be looking at
P25, because what we are doing is we are unnecessarily penalizing
kind of an artifact of speculatively loading
again, the goal.
If you don't understand the detail, that's fine.
The goal of this slide is when you're thinking about percentiles,
when you're thinking about silver, you need to take a deeper, deeper dive on
what what different optimizations are doing to your distributions
and how do you want to match them against customer expectations.
So it does require kind of a two bit more in-depth kind of digging into your data,
rather than kind of simple chatbot style workloads.
The other thing that you need to think about.
So I have two colorful blocks here.
Different rows are basically user,
user one, user two, user three, user four.
And what this slide is trying to convey is if you ignore the tools
tool part of it, you're not really measuring the right
workload again.
So on the left side I'm assuming there is no tool call.
So there is none of that purple block that I showed where the
kind of things are running on the CPU.
In that case, what you ended up saying is user one, user
two, user three, user four
are fully packing my elements or fully packing my GPUs.
So this whole bridge is basically when your large language model is being called.
But in
reality, that's not the case when you are running close.
This is not how your GPUs look like.
You're not continuously kind of keeping your GPS busy.
What is happening is you run your large language models and then actually
you are running tool calls which are which are running on your CPU.
So actually your GPU is not doing any work during that time.
And depending on how big that variation
is, you can actually support more users because you are effectively
not packing GPUs as much as you can.
So just ignoring the concept that there is no tool actually ends up
predicting the wrong concurrency or wrong workload
that that that you can support on your hardware.
And there are some metrics there, like if you assume
one call takes one second,
if you have a tool call that takes one second, two and half of your areas,
you can actually support twice the number of users than you thought,
because a bunch of that work load is being done on CPU two.
So again, that the crux of this slide is make sure you are representing
your workload correctly, especially in a generic workloads.
Those gray regions where this stuff is being run on CPU is very important,
and that kind of helps you getting the right number of
kind of users you can support for a given worker.
So that's the tool side of things.
Now this this is the last piece
on kind of what is missing in the current workloads.
And this is again
a subtle piece when you're talking about agent workloads.
Again
the metrics take some time to stabilize.
So if you are looking at the same metrics that are talked about,
the time to first token and speed,
you can see like in the beginning
when the cache is not warmed up, things are still in the transient state.
Your metrics is still evolving.
So if you would have measured your performance at this point
and assume that your slow was 10 seconds for TTFT, you would have said that
this deployment is filled, that it's a lower, which is not the case.
It's just that this is still in the ground state.
It starts stabilized yet.
And that is just because again, with the agent workflows,
the caches are coming into play.
There are much more high level of optimizations that are coming into play.
So they need time to stabilize.
So make sure we are looking at this metrics.
You are sure that the metrics
that you are kind of focused on is has stabilized.
And some curves like that where you plot the metrics over time
and see if you see flat flatness towards the end is a way to do that.
And just to reiterate the same point, the same story here holds for the speed.
So if these were your slow lines, you would have said that this is
a bad deployment and you would have said, now we need you the more details,
whereas if you would have just let the system stabilize,
you would have said,
this is a perfectly well deployment which matches both of these SLOs.
So now I just want to
give you an example of a benchmark that is trying to close this graph.
This is a benchmark from artificial analysis.
It's a third party benchmarking company.
And they came up with this benchmark a couple of weeks ago.
The results are still not out.
So in a few weeks of time you can see different
hardware players and how they did on this benchmark.
But it does enable most of the things that we talked about.
KV cache-aware routing in multi-tenant is along with speculative decoding,
the slow based setup that we just talked about.
It's it's for two models deep before and GPT us 120 for now.
And this this list will grow.
And the way they are going to end the and the question that they are trying
to answer is they are given three slots, for example, there
where they have an SLO, how fast your alarm
should generate the tokens, what is the time to first token.
And now you can imagine another column here
which says to meet this as a loan for a given hardware.
How many users can I sustain?
So that's the question that they are trying to answer for each of these slots.
What's the maximum number of users a given hardware can sustain.
And you should see numbers for different hardware and things like that.
And they have curated this whole data set multi-tenant trajectory
real world data set.
So this is trying to close that gap.
In addition to that, it will also show kind of what metrics
and kind of some some per dollar metrics also.
So keep an eye out attention analysis is
this benchmark is going to start kind of closing some of the gaps
that I talked about. And it's going
to get more and more towards the real agentic workloads like that.
Most of the production applications are.
Just bringing everything together.
We talked about multi-tenant trajectories, very important.
We talked about different kinds of optimization, caching and routing
speculative decoding.
We talked about how to think about performance
in terms of the sellers rather than means and medians.
We talked about how tools become very important
in this case, and we talked about the steady state
to make sure that the metrics, the metrics that is, you are not measuring something
that is still in the transient state and has has stabilized.
Again, as I said, this is still the beginning.
This is like the bread and butter of agentic verticals.
What's still missing is a lot.
And this field is going to still evolve and we are going to get better and better
multi-agent workflows.
Still, I'm talking about single trajectory one agent doing interacting with two.
How about when multiple agents are interacting?
What do you think? How do you think
about kind of benchmarking in that case quality in the cloud?
I kind of skipped the whole
accuracy is how good your agent is, how fast you can solve something.
I primarily focused on performance, but you need to couple these things together,
how fast your model can run
and how good is the model actually solving a particular task.
Long running sessions agents are becoming longer and longer.
You can let their agents run for two days.
Three days. How do you think about performance data?
Because now you're getting cash, or cash is continuously growing.
You need to manage that memory somehow.
Heterogeneous workload.
This was all coded.
How about different kinds of agent for close CPU coupling?
We didn't even talk
about how the CPU comes into play,
which is kind of talked about delays and things like that.
But in this case, now GPU and CPU have to play together to make things
work efficiently.
And there are different kinds of metrics.
You can talk about task completion time rather than what what I talked about.
So a lot of work on what the good metrics look like.
So so in short, today's benchmarks have caught up to chat
bot area and kind of chatbot world.
But the benchmarks for word are still being built
and we are just getting started.
There's still a long way to go, but benchmarks like it.
Artificial intelligence agent for benchmark is trying to close that gap.
With that, I'm going to
end my talk and happy to take any questions you have.
Questions?
Oh, one very eager question down here.
Can we get a mic down here please, friends?
Thank you for the nice presentation.
I have a question about speculative decoding.
Does it work with non-zero modal temperatures,
or is this all just about benchmarking?
Assumes that all users on server use zero modal temperatures.
Now it does work with non-zero non-zero temperatures.
Can you give us a bit details? How?
I don't imagine so.
How model can verify something that was randomly picked from choice.
So so so so the distribution is still matches.
So so when you talk about kind of matching the distributions of these two.
So this
you are still sampling from a distribution right.
Even for a struggle at decoding or not just randomly going
and picking up anything.
So if your distribution is still matches, you still have higher probability
of predicting what the target is going to produce. Right?
So so it's still still.
Yeah I think I have
another question over here.
So thank you for.
Your time to first token and speed histograms.
Are you running those on the same workflow the same requests
or are you doing that cross your kind of whole suite
of kind of agent requests.
This is for
do you mean is it just agentic or is.
It kind of like a running the same prompt through that.
No, no. This is. The multiple.
So that, that,
that example that I had in the beginning was just an example of a trajectory.
And you can imagine like hundreds and thousands of these things
that we have collected
and are running against them, against the hardware to get these numbers.
So you would with that, you would expect a harder problem
to be longer to the first token anyway, wouldn't you?
So so
this is where caching comes into play, right?
So so if most of your
refill is cached,
what you are doing the work together, time to first token is just this cube.
Extra work if the caching goes off.
Yes you at the last kind of.
At this point you will be doing something like that
which is doing computation for this whole input input field,
which yes, obviously your TTFT will be much worse, but because of
caching, your, your, your TTFT is kind of just constrained by that new piece.
And I think we are also trying to ask is because of the trajectory,
the time to first.
So the time to first token here still means for a request
for one of these kind of one of these green blocks time.
The first token is not when your answers that's coming.
Let me say that that's another.
No, that makes sense.
Yeah. You got it back on. Yeah.
I was just thinking if, for example, one of your tool called came out with
like a really long response and it really struggled to chime through that,
then you'd expect a really high peak to get to that type of token,
because it would be working through a harder problem. Exactly.
And that's why the prefix caching is like the bread
and butter for optimizing the design clothes.
And it's a shame that agent
most of the benchmarks don't capture that and know that you can't do that.
So yeah. Really interesting. Thank you.
Okay.
I'm afraid
we're out of time there, but would you be happy to answer a few questions? Yes.
So yeah, please do come and find a it for more questions.
But in the meanwhile, thank you very much.